(Sheldon:)Of course.
(Sheldon:)First, consider an ordinary magnet,
which has, as even the most uneducated...
[VOICE BECOMING HIGH-PITCHED]
...in your audience must know, two poles...
[CLEARS THROAT]
(Sheldon:)...a north and south pole.
(Sheldon:)If you cut that in half,
you have two smaller magnets...
(Sheldon:)...each with its own north
and south pole.
(Ira:)Dr. Cooper, I think there might be
something wrong with our connection.
(Sheldon(even higher pitch):)No, I hear you fine.
(Sheldon(even higher pitch):)As I was saying,
an ordinary magnet has two poles.
(Sheldon(even higher pitch):)The primary characteristic
of a monopole...
(Sheldon(even higher pitch):)...is that it has only one pole,
hence, "monopole."
SHELDON: A requirement for string theory,
or M-theory, if you will...
(Sheldon:)...is the existence of such monopoles.
(Sheldon:)I myself led an expedition to the
Arctic Circle in search of said particles.
(Sheldon:)Kripke, I found the nozzle.
I'm going to kill you.
[ALL LAUGHING]